as someone who's nervous system is
basically allergic to stress living in a
society that glorifies stress and
striving and go go go go go
I've had to develop a lot of coping
mechanisms in order to simply exist and
in this heightened stressful anxious
time I now have the capacity to pass
that learning on to other people so this
is a list of 12 things I have found that
helped me reduce my stress and anxiety
and hopefully they help you to number
one allow yourself to feel emotions
there are no good and bad emotions allow
grief and anger to wash over you and
then dissipate find constructive ways to
express these emotions to you have
unique challenges allow others to do
what is easy for them and find ways that
you that are easy for you to contribute
we are better and less stressed together
ask for help what is difficult for you
is easy for someone else and vice-versa
contribute in your unique way because
contribution feels good
unique contribution feels even better 3
focus on the good for at least part of
the day what did you do today what do
you have to be happy about allow
yourself to feel gratitude for the good
for love love yourself love your friends
and family love strangers just let the
sweet sweet oxytocin a flow wash over
you
5 laughs anytime you can life is full of
contradictions this list is full of
contradictions isn't life grand laugh at
the absurdity 6 meditate retrain your
nervous system that life is not scary
and you are safe then when actual
hazards come you have more capacity to
deal with them 7 learn to listen to your
inner wisdom we are all different with
unique things to learn give - we have
unique things to
and to be given eight you are the only
you the world has be you you cannot
compare yourself to anyone else nor any
two people to each other comparison is
the thief of joy celebrate your
successes do not grade yourself on a
curve 9 do what makes you happy
learn only what excites you do
activities that bring you joy let go of
the shoulds and allow for what you want
do not consume art science media that
you think you should consume simply
because you should 10 let go of what
others think of you
or what you think others think of you
other people's opinions of you and how
you live your life is none of your
business
if they have a problem it is just that
their problem 11 surrender to what is
every experience can teach you if you
were open most discomfort comes from
resistance to what is
and 12 allow yourself slow imperceptible
at times loving progress accepting
yourself as you are and the situation as
they are that is 12 things I have found
to deal with stress in my daily life and
now I am finding as the world explodes
and stress and anxiety I am better able
to cope with this pandemic than other
people because I've developed these
techniques but their techniques I've
developed over years and every one of
them has been a layered learning
I didn't just learn it and now I exist
in it and all of them I continue to
learn but this can be a time of
rejuvenation for you and for the planet
and allowing yourself to concentrate on
the good and the beautiful every day so
you can feel good in your body is a gift
you can give yourself
it doesn't mean cancelling out all of
the negative it doesn't mean forcing
positivity on yourself and others but
allow yourself to feel joy and laughter
and gratitude even in these difficult
times thank you